A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Librarian of Virginia, 1832-2024 Jan
Library of Virginia
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1827-2007.
  - 1879-1992; Bulk 1975-1990 (Accession 34229)., 23 cu. ft. (23 boxes)
    - State Aid, 1991. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - State Aid, 1989-1990. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - State Aid, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - State Aid, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - State Aid, 1987. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - State and Federal Aid, 1987-1989. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - State and Federal Aid, 1985. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - State and Federal Aid, 1965-1968. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - State and Federal Aid, 1952-1959. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - State and Federal Aid, 1949. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - State Council on Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV), 1989-1990. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - State Data, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - State Fair, 1987-1990. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - State Historical Records Advisory Board, 1987-1989. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - State Public Records Advisory Council, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - State Public Records Council, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - State Publications In Print, 1987-1989. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - State Networking Users Advisory Board (SNUAB, 1988-1990. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Statistics, 1987-1990. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Summer Reading Program, 1987-1989. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Superintendent of Documents, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Supervisory Staff Meetings, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Surveys, 1987; 1990. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Sutton, Ann: Memorial Book Fund, 1984. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - T: Letters, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Teleconference, 1987; 1989. (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Telefax, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Telefax, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Telefax, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Telefax, 1987. (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Telephone Survey, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Thank you notes, 1986-1989. (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Theft: Replevin - Washington Family Documents, 1988 Oct 20. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Training, 1989-1990. (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Travel: American World Tours, 1984-1985. (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Travel Cards, 1989 August 7. (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Travel Reimbursement, 1990 Aug 10. (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Treasury Board, 1990 Apr 6. (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Treasury Loan, 1990 July 2. (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Trist, Douglas: Letters, 1985-1989. (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Trustees, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - United Way, 1987. (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1986-1988. (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare: Letters of Credit, 1976; 1978-1981. (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor: Employment Standards Administration, 1988-1989. (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - U.S. Postal Service: Zip Codes, 1981 Aug. (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - V: Letters, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Valentine Museum, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Vendors, 1990 Mar 8. (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Video Conference, 1986-1989. (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Virginia: 400th Anniversary, 1986. (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Virginia Cavalcade, 1968; 1971-1972. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Cavalcade, 1961-1972. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Executive Institute, 1988-1989. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Historical Society, 1988. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Institute for Law and Citizenship Studies, Inc., 1988. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Legislation, 1990. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Library Association, 1987-1990. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Library Network, 1989. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Library Networking Task Force, 1988. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Literacy Coalition, 1986-1987. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Literacy Initiative, 1987. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Public Library Directors Association, 1988-1989. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Virginia State Library Supervisors Packet, 1986-1987. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Virginia State Library Supervisors Packet, 1986. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Tech Library Systems, 1987-1988. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Visually Handicapped, 1990. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - VITA, undated. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Volunteers, undated. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Voter Registration, 1990. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - W: Letters, 1988. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Wage Employees, 1990. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - War Memorial, 1990. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Washington Council of Governments, 1970-1987. (Box 12, Folder 23-34)
    - White House Council on Library and Information Science, 1984-1991. (Box 12, Folder 35-37)
    - White House Council on Library and Information Science, 1968-1990. (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
    - Y: Letters, 1988. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Code Commission, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Emergency and Energy, 1984. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Engineering and Building, 1984. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Executive Agreement, 1983-1984. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: General Services, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: General Services, 1985. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: George Mason, 1983. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office, 1985. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Highways and Transportations, 1984. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: House of Delegates, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: House of Delegates, 1983. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Information and Technology, 1985. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Planning and Budget, 1984. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Planning and Budget, 1983. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Purchase and Supply, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Secretary of Administration, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Secretary of Education, 1986-1983. (Box 13, Folder 22-26)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Universities, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - A-Z: Letters, 1986. (Box 14, Folder 1-20)
    - A-W: Letters, 1985. (Box 14, Folder 21-42)
    - A-W: Letters, 1984. (Box 14, Folder 43-62)
    - A-I: Letters, 1983. (Box 14, Folder 63-71)
    - J-Z: Letters, 1983. (Box 15, Folder 1-14)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Accounts, Department of, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Administration, Secretary of, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Administration, Secretary of, 1978-1980; 1982-1984. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Alcohol Beverage Conrtol Board, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Art Commission, 1948-1949. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Attorney General, 1929-1988. (Box 15, Folder 20-25)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Attorney General - Burwell, Lewis, 1972; 1976-1978. (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Auditor of Public Accounts, 1987-1988. (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Baliles, Mrs. Jeannie, 1987-1988. (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Central Garage Carpool, 1988. (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Chief of Staff, 1987-1988. (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Children, Department of, 1988. (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Code Commission, 1988. (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Comptroller, Ofiice of the, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Commonwealth, Secretary of, 1987-1989. (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Conservation and Historic Resources, Department of, 1987-1988. (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Council on Information Management, 1989. (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Education, Department of, 1980-1989. (Box 15, Folder 37-38)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Education, Secretary of, 1979-1990. (Box 15, Folder 39-40)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Engineering and Building, Department of, 1977-1988. (Box 15, Folder 41-44)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Executive Institute, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: General Services, Department of, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Blood Donor Committee, 1975. (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office, 1980-1989. (Box 15, Folder 48-51)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Commonwealth, Secretary of, 1988. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Education Aide Memorandums, 1975 Apr 18. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: General Services, Dept. of, 1988. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - CETA Program, 1975. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - Correspondence, 1987-1989. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - Dendy, 1987-1988. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - Executive Memorandums, 1978-1990. (Box 16, Folder 7-17)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - Eecutive Policy, 1983; 1985. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - Letters, 1987-1988. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Governor's Office - Secretariats, 1987 Sept. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Health and Human Resources, 1988. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Highway Dept., 1988. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Information Technology, Dept. of, 1987-1990. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Information Technology, Dept. of, 1985. (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Information Technology, Dept. of, 1984. (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Information Technology, Dept. of, 1984. (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Jamestown Foundation, 1987. (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Joint Legislative Audit Review Commission, 1987-1988. (Box 16, Folder 28-33)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1984. (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Land Office, 1982-1983. (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Legislative Automated Systems, 1987. (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Library, State, 1965; 1967; 1969-72; 1983. (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Management Analysis and Systems Development, 1980; 1983. (Box 16, Folder 38-39)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1987 Mar 18. (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Military Affairs, Dept. of, 1986 Feb. (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Minority Business Enterprise, 1988 May. (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Personnel and Training, 1978-1988. (Box 16, Folder 43-46)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Planning and Budget, 1978; 1987. (Box 16, Folder 47-48)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Public Buildings Commission, 1982. (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Public Records, 1983; 1988. (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Purchase and Supply, Dept. of, 1978-1979. (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Rehabilitative Services, 1980-1982. (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Risk Management, 1988. (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: State Council on Higher Education for Virginia, 1978-1988. (Box 16, Folder 54-58)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: State Fair, 198. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: State Historical Records Advisory Board, 1988. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - State Network User Advisory Board, 1987-1990. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - State Network User Advisory Board, 1986-1988. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - State Network User Advisory Council, 1982, 1984-1986. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - State Network User Advisory Council, 1981-1984. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - State Network User Advisory Board, 1977, 1980, 1982-1984. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - State Public Records Advisory Council, 1976-1979, 1980-1982, 1984, 1988. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Supply, Dept. of - Price Agreements, 1981. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Taxation, Dept. of, 1969, 1982. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Telecommunications, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Transportation, Dept. of, 1987, 1990. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Transportation, 1983. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Treasury, Dept. of, 1987-1988. (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1987-1988. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: University of Virginia, 1984-1985. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, 1942-1943. (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Virginia Film Office, 1988. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Virginia State Library, 1978-1979. (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Visually Handicapped, 1988. (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Visually Handicapped, 1987. (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Welfare, Dept. of, 1978-1990. (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Welfare, Dept. of, 1978. (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Welfare, Dept. of, 1978. (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: Welfare, Dept. of, 1977-1978. (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Virginia Commonwealth: William and Mary College, 1988. (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - A-95 Proclaimation, 1980-1981. (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Approved Audits, 1970. (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Approved Audits (Federal), 1964-1966, 1968. (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Title II, 1971-1975. (Box 17, Folder 30-32)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, 1968-1970; Undated. (Box 17, Folder 33-37)
    - Letter of Credit, 1976, 1980. (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Library Services and Construction Act, 1977-1988. (Box 17, Folder 39-46)
    - Actual Expenditures, 1973-1974. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Amended Conditions for Payment, 1966. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Amended Conditions for Payment, 1967. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Amended State Plan, 1965-1966. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report, 1975. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report - Statistical Summary, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report - Title I, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report - Title IV B, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Expenditures, 1972. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Expenditures, 1971. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Expenditures, 1969. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Expenditures, 1975-1976. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Expenditures, 1974. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Expenditures, 1972. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Expenditures, 1971. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Expenditures, 1970. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Expenditures, 1969. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Federal Programs, 1984. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Final Allotments, 1975 June. (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Final Allotments, 1973-1974. (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Final Allotments, 1972-1973. (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Final Allotments, 1971-1972. (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Final Allotments, 1971-1972. (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Final Allotments, 1971. (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, 1970-1971. (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, 1970. (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, 1969. (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, 1969. (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, 1967. (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Health, Education and Welfare - Audit, Undated. (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Library Service and Construction Act, 1976-1981. (Box 18, Folder 31-37)
    - Revenue Sharing, 1972. (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - State Advisory Council on Libraries, 1975. (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - State Plan, 1966-1979. (Box 18, Folder 40-46)
    - Tenative Allotments, 1969-1974. (Box 18, Folder 47-50)
    - Title I, 1975. (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Title I - Approved, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Title I, II, III, IV A, IV B, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Title III, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Title IV, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - Title IV B, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Collections - Deposits, Undated. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Collections - Miscellaneous, 1877-1961. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Collections - Painting and Statuary, 1874-1962. (Box 19, Folder 3-21)
    - Collections - Scope of, 1903-1981. (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Collections - Want List, 1935. (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Inscriptions and Memorials, Undated, 1907-1972. (Box 19, Folder 24-25)
    - Loans, 1928-1988. (Box 19, Folder 26-30)
    - Model of the Capitol, 1940-1976. (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Portraits and Pieces of Statuary - List of, 1920. (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Portrait Bulletin, 1958. (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Portraits - Receipts, 1931-1943. (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Restoration of Portraits, 1974. (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - McIlwaine Memorial, 1946-1947. (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Report of the State Librarian, 1971-1978. (Box 19, Folder 37-41)
    - Report of the State Librarian, 1941-1974. (Box 20, Folder 1-31)
    - Report of the State Librarian, 1928-1941. (Box 21, Folder 1-9)
    - Report of the Assistant State Librarian, 1941-1974. (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
    - Report of the State Archivist, 1947-1915. (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
    - Report of the Extension Division, 1925-1945. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Report of the Periodicals Division, 1916-1938. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Report of the Photostat Division, 1926-1939. (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Report of the Publications Division, 1947. (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Report of the Reference Division, 1930-1941. (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Report of Robinson, Morgan P., 1927-1937. (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Reports, Statistical, 1917-1938. (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Annual Report, 1977-1985. (Box 21, Folder 22-28)
    - Highway Historical Markers, 1949-1971. (Box 21, Folder 29-31)
    - Survey, 1967-1969. (Box 21, Folder 32-34)
    - Consultants: Little Survey, 1968-1969. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Consultants: Little Survey, 1965-1969. (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
    - Letters: A- W, 1987; 1988. (Box 22, Folder 6-31)
    - Letters: L, 1990-1991. (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Philip Morris Newsletter, 1991. (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Programming, 1989. (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - SOLINET, 1987. (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Staff Memos from Yates, 1988. (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - TDD, 1989. (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Telecommunications, 1989. (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Historic Landmarks, 1960-1987. (Box 22, Folder 39-89)
    - Historic Landmarks, 1986. (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Building Files, 1984-1988. (Box 23, Folder 3-23)
    - Building: Dewberry and Davis, 1987. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Public Library Plans: Alexandria, 1966-1969. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Public Library Plans: Arlington, 1964-1968. (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    - Public Library Plans: Botetourt-Rockingham, 1966-1969. (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
    - Public Library Plans: Alexandria, 1966-1969. (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
    - Public Library Plans: McIntire, 1965-1968. (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
    - Public Library Plans: Norfolk, 1966-1969. (Box 24, Folder 11-13)
    - Public Library Plans: Pulaski, 1965-1968. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Public Library Plans: Roanoke, 1965-1968. (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Public Library Plans: Rockingham, 1966-1969. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Public Library Plans: Virginia Beach, 1965-1969. (Box 24, Folder 19-20)
  - 1903-1953 (Accession 28366)., .5 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    This collection contains correspondence to and from the State Librarians, John Pendleton Kennedy, Henry Read McIllwaine, and Wilmer L. Hall. Correspondents include but are not limited to Library of Congress, B.F. Stevens and Brown of London, England, churches, universities and libraries. Topics discussed are genealogical research, publications: "Bulletins," Executive Journals of Colonial Councils, Journal of the House of Burgesses, Letters of the Governor's, St. Peter's Parrish, and Senate Journals. Included are letters, memoranda, photocopies, proofs, and drafts.
    - Correspondence with B.F. Steven and Brown, LTD, 1928-1929. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence about material other than Executive Journals, 1908-1931. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Maps; Letters and other Data used for compiling a list of Virginia Maps, 1912-1914. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Public Record Office Investigations, 1903-1953. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Publications - General, 1939-1941. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Publications - Annual Reports, 1906-1914. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Publications - Blisland Parish, 1931-1935. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Publications - Bulletins, 1912-1941. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Publications - Bulletins, Bibliography of Virginia, 1936. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Publications - Bulletin, Virginia Counties, 1915-1941. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Publications - Bulletins, Checklist, 1948. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Publications - Executive Journals of Colonial Council, General, 1920-1947. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Publications - Executive Journals of Colonial Council, Vol. 5, 1941-1946. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Publications - Executive Journals of Colonial Council, Vol. 5 Editor's Notes, 1941-1946. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Publications - Executive Journal of Colonial Council, Vol. 6, 1927; 1942. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Publications - Executiv Journals of the Colonial Council, Proclaimations, 1927-1928. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Publications - Journals of the House of Burgesses, 1904-1918. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Publications - Legislative Journals of the Council, 1916-1918. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Publications - Official Letters of the Governors, 1925-1926. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Publications - St. Paul's Parish, Undated. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Publications - St. Peter's Parish, 1936-1944. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Publications - Senate Journals, 1951. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1903-1968 (Accession 28078)., 72.45 (212 boxes)
    This collection contains correspondence to and from the State Librarians, John Pendleton Kennedy, Henry Read McIllwaine, Wilmer L. Hall, and Randolph W. Church. Correspondents include but are not limited to State Archivist Morgan P. Robinson, patrons, researchers, historical societies, social groups, state and federal agencies, universities, libraries, museums and vendors. Topics discussed are "Virginia Cavalcade," preservation, subscriptions, publications, and resolutions. Included are letters, invoices, invitations, memoranda, photographs, brochures, and "Thank You" notes. There are also copies of overdue book notices which were sent personaly by the state librarian. Box 92 folder 2 contains a letter from Carl E. Milliken, the executive secretary of the Motion Picture Producers and Distributors Association, regarding a history of film writen by, Will H. Hays, President of the association, the book is still part of the circulating collection at the library. Box 101 folder 1 contains an invitation requesting the state librarian's prescence at Mary Baldwin college for the presidential vist of Dwight D. Eisenhower. The library also held a national contest, seeking a painter to produce a mural for the lobby of the state library, box 104 folder 14 contains the responses of solicited artists, among them are Leo Katz and Lee Woodward Zeigler. Box 130 folder 5 contains a letter from RKO studios inquiring about facts relating to Jefferson Davis for a picture they were working on which was set in Richmond durring the Civil War.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title, with general correspondence first, followed by more specific folders when applicable, there are some exceptions as original order has been maintained and inconsistencies exist in the filing. Correspondnece is alphabetized using surname of sender, institute of origin or location.